자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)
해럴드!
Harold!
일찍 오셨네요
You're early.
나도 알아. 가져갈 물건이 있어서
I know.
I'm picking something up.
페기는 어디 있어요?
Where's Peggy?
언제나 꼭 붙어다니시더니
Thought you two were joined at the hip.
- 여보세요
- 일은 어떻게 되어가지, 해럴드?
Yes? / How's it going, Harold?
지금 들어와서
시키는 대로 하는 중이에요
I'm in. I'm doing it.
널 생각해서 다시 알려주는 건데
Friendly reminder.
영웅 노릇 하려 들진 마
Don't be a hero.
경찰 사이렌이 들리는 순간
페기 목숨은 없는 줄 알아
We hear a police siren,
Peggy's dead.
- 무사한가요? 목소리 좀 들려 줘요
- 서두르기나 해
Is she okay?
Can I talk to her?
Just hurry up.
제발 얘기만 하게 해 주...
Please let me just talk to...
잠깐만, 여, 여보세요?
Hel, let me, hello?
뒷좌석으로 와
Back seat.
이제 보내 주세요
약속했잖습니까
Let her go.
You said you would.
같이 일해서 즐거웠어
Pleasure doing business with you.
- 차도 줘서 고마워, 해럴드
- 이리 온, 페기
- Thanks for the car, Harold.
- Come here, Peggy.
해럴드!
Harold!
- 별일 없으신 겁니까?
- 폴, 난 괜찮아
- Everything all right?
- Paul, I'm okay.
아무 문제없어
No problem.
차에서 내려!
Get out of the car!
두 놈 다! 당장!
Both of you!
Do it!
알았어
Okay!
할로윈인데 어디 안 가나?
Happy halloween, man.
진정하라고
Just relax.
빅! 무슨 짓이야? / 놈 아니면
내가 죽으니 어쩔 수 없었어
Vic! What did you do?
No choice. Him or me.
얼른 차를 몰고 뜨자
차에 타!
We could've just driven off!
Get in the car!
전 아무것도 못 봤어요
I didn't see anything.
- 당신 얼굴도요
- 차를 움직이지 마
- I didn't see your face.
- Don't move the car.
- 아직 볼일 안 끝났어, 괜찮아?
- 페기도 못 봤대요, 안 그래 아가?
- I'm not done. You okay?
- Neither did Peggy, did you, sweetie?
난 볼일 안 끝났다고
I'm not done.
안 돼!
No!
MONK Season 4 Epi. 1
Mr. Monk and the Other Detective
토니 샬롭
(에이드리안 몽크 役)
트레일러 하워드
(나탈리 티거 役)
제이슨 그레이 스탠포드
(랜달 디셔 경위 役)
테드 리바인
(리랜드 스토틀마이어 경감 役)
딕테이션
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
싱크편집
윤선영(seedyun@nate.com)
한글번역
한상희(fithelestre@sanori.net)
ORIGINAL AIR DATE ON USA: 2005/07/08
몽크, 괜찮아요?
- 몽크와 또 다른 명탐정 -
Mr. Monk, are you okay?
다들 기다리고 있어요
- 몽크와 또 다른 명탐정 -
Everybody's waiting.
저기 있어요
It's over there.
뭐가요?
What?
개, 그러니까...
Dog, you know.
개 응가가요
Dog doo...
그걸 밟았어요?
Did you step in it?
밟았으면 지금 저 구급차에 실려
응급실로 가고 있겠죠, 안 그래요?
If I stepped in it,
I'd be in that ambulance right now
on my way to the emergency
room, wouldn't I?
차라리 죽어서 이 모든 고통이
덜어졌으면 하고 바라면서요
Praying for the sweet release
that only death can bring.
몽크, 어떻게 생각하나?
범인은 어떤 자일 것 같나?
So, Monk, what do you think?
Who are we looking for?
글쎄, 아마도 테리어 같습니다
요크셔거나 치와와일 수도 있겠죠
Uh, I'd say it's a terrier.
A yorkie, maybe a chihuahua.
지금쯤 몇 마일은 족히 갔을 테니
절대 잡을 수 없을 겁니다
Probably miles away by now.
We'll never catch him.
몽크 씬 지금 집중이 안 되셔서...
He can't concentrate
because of the...
뭣 때문에요?
Because of the what?
개 응가요
The dog poo.
디셔!
Lieutenant?
저것 좀 치워 주게
Clean that up for me, would you?
수고해
Thanks.
경사!
Sergeant?
예, 경위님?
Yes, sir?
저것 좀 치워줘
Clean that up.
돌아보지 말아요
No, don't.
거기 주차하시면 안 됩니다
Sir, you can't park there.
괜찮아요, 괜찮아
It's all right. It's okay.
전 탐정이거든요
I'm a detective.
탐정입니다
잠깐 기다리시면 보여드리죠
One second. Here we go.
여기, 이것 좀 들고 계세요
Here we, um, hold that.
찾았어요
I got it.
보통 여기에 꽂아두는데...
I usually keep it right...
아, 찾았어요
Oh, I got it.
여기 있습니다
마티 일즈, 사립탐정이죠
Here we go.
Marty Eels, private investigator.
여러분을 구해 드리려 왔어요
I'm here to save your butts.
반장님!
Captain!
- 스토틀마이어 반장님!
- 이런 젠장
- Captain Stottlemeyer!
- Oh, hell.
저 사람 누군데요?
Who's that?
마티 일즈라는 사립탐정이야
Marty Eels.
He's a private investigator.
이혼, 보험 사기 같은
자잘한 일만 맡고 다니지
Nickel and dime stuff.
Divorces, insurance fraud.
정말 같이 일하기 싫은 녀석이야
He's a professional pain in the ass.
반장님, 풍채 좋아지셨네요
Hey, captain.
Captain, you're looking great.
살이 빠지셨거나
셔츠가 늘어났나 봅니다
You're losing weight or
your shirts are getting bigger.
마티
Marty.
지방검사한테 면허를 뺏겼다고 들었는데
I heard the D.A. pulled your license.
아뇨, 잠시 정지된 것뿐이에요
No, no, that was just
a temporary suspension.
정말 별일 아닙니다
사소한 오해가 있었어요
No, no, no. No, no. That was just
a little misunderstanding.
- 오해라니?
- 뭐 다 옛날 얘기죠, 어쨌든...
A misunderstanding?
Well, that's all ancient
history anyway, so...
어쩌다 보니 차 몰고
이 동네를 지나고 있었는데
so I was just, you know, riding
around in the neighborhood.
순찰차 무선으로 호출하는
내용을 듣게 되어서...
And I heard a call go out
on the police scanner, and...
마티, 난 바쁜 몸이네
Look, Marty, I'm busy.
예, 그래서 일손 좀 빌려 드리려고
여기 찾아온 겁니다
Yeah, yeah, that's why I thought
I'd come down here and lend a hand.
어떻게 된 일이죠?
보석상이 강도를 당했죠
So what do we got?
The jewelry store was robbed.
그거야 다 아는 거고
Well, that's obvious.
상점 경비원 한 명이 죽고
지배인은 실종됐죠
We got a dead rent-a-cop
and a missing store manager.
그러니 여러분은 지배인이 이런
짓을 저질렀다고 생각하시겠죠
So, let me guess, you're thinking
the store manager's doing this...
- 그래, 그런 셈이야
- 저도 좀 둘러봐도 되죠?
Yeah, something like that.
So let me look around, huh?
살펴보는 눈이 두 개 더 생긴다고
뭐 크게 문제 되겠습니까?
I mean, an extra pair
of eyes can't hurt.
알게 뭡니까? 여러분이 놓친
실마리를 제가 찾을지
And who knows? I could see
something you guys are missing.
아무것도 놓치진 않습니다, 일즈 씨
We're not missing anything, Mr. Eels.
감식반도 와 있거든요
We've got a CSI team here.
또 저기 있는 사람 보이시나요?
And, uh, see that man over there?
에이드리안 몽크죠
모든 상황은 완벽히 통제되고 있습니다
That's Adrian Monk.
I think we're in pretty good hands.
반장님, 몽크 씨가 이걸
아무 데나 버리지 말라는데요
Captain, Monk says I can't
just throw this away.
잘 챙겨서 1마일쯤
떨어진 곳에 묻으래요
I gotta take it, like,
a mile away and bury it.
- 제가 좀 봐도 되나요?
- 그러세요
Could I see that?
Yeah.
그냥 버리면 안 되죠
이것도 증거 아닙니까
You can't throw this away.
This, this is evidence.
금방 누었나 본데요
This is fresh.
1시간 반도 안 된 것
같아요 / 마티...
I'd say this is less than
90 minutes old. / Marty...
사건이 벌어진 시각으로
추정하신 때랑 일치하지 않나요?
But isn't that when you said
all this was probably going down?
개는 피해자의 소유이거나
범인들의 것일 겁니다
The dog could've belonged to the victim
or to one of the perps.
중요한 증거 같은데요
몽크가 이걸 내다 버리라고 하다니
I think this is important.
Monk was gonna throw this away.
음...
Um...
이 친구 말이 맞는지도 모르겠군
You know, he might be right.
에, 증거물로 보관해두게
Let's, um, book that into evidence.
- 알겠습니다
- 반장님, 보세요
- Yes, sir.
- Captain, look.
상점 매니저가 오클랜드에 살았었나요?
Did that store manager live in Oakland?
그렇긴 한데 어떻게 아셨어요?
Yeah, how'd you know that?
그 사람의 개입니다
That's his dog.
오클랜드에서 왔군요
That's from Oakland.
목줄에 달린 푸른 등록증이
보이실 겁니다
You can see the blue license
on its collar.
아니 자넨 그게 여기서 보여?
What, you can see that from here?
"세부 사항에 집중하는 능력"
이라고 부르는 거죠
A little something I call
"attention to detail." but...
가서 개 데려와
Go get the dog.
이쪽은 에이드리안 몽크, 나탈리 티거
이쪽은 마티 일즈일세
Adrian Monk, Natalie Teeger,
this is Marty Eels.
- 사립탐정이야
- 안녕하십니까?
- He's a private investigator.
- Hey, how you doing?
안녕하세요?
소문은 익히 들었습니다
How you doing?
I hear good things. Good things.
염려 놓으세요, 경쟁하러 온 게
아니라 도와주러 온 것뿐이니까요
Don't worry. I'm not competition.
I'm just here to help.
저도 한 장 주시면 안 될까요?
Can I have one of those?
자...
So...
지금까지 알아내신 게 있나요?
what have we got?
반장님, 지배인의 소행 같지 않아요
Captain, I don't think
the manager did this.
우선 나가면서 문을 잠그지도 않았고
For one thing, he didn't lock
the door behind him.
게다가 인도의 연석 옆에
더 많은 피가 묻어 있거든요
Plus, I notice some
more blood by the curb.
총격이 2번 있었던 것 같아요
I think there was a second shooting.
일리가 있군요
Yeah, he could be right.
아주 좋아요, 잘했어요
Very good. Nicely done.
- 잘했어요, 고마워요. 아가씨
- 반장님!
- Nicely done. Thanks, sweetheart.
- Captain!
이분 말이 맞았어요
He's right.
상점 지배인이 기르던 개 같습니다
I think he belongs to the store manager.
해럴드 검벌
오클랜드 기어리 가라고 쓰여 있거든요
Harold Gumbal. Geary st., Oakland.
아시다시피 지배인이
자기 가게를 털었다면
You know, if the manager was
robbing his own store,
애완견을 데려오지 않았겠죠
he wouldn't bring his dog along.
내버리고 가지도 않았을 거고요
Or leave him behind.
지배인 소행은 아니에요
No, the manager is not the guy.
맞습니다
매니저는 범인이 아니에요
No, that's right.
The manager is not the guy.
- 사건의 진상은...
- 사건의 진상은 이렇습니다
- Here's what happ...
- Here's what happened.
사건의 진상은 이렇습니다!
이 개가 인질이었던 거죠
Here's what happened!
This dog was a hostage.
지배인은 자기 가게를 털도록
협박당한 거예요
The manager was being forced
to rob his store.
뭔가 일이 꼬이자
진범들이 경비원을 쐈습니다
Something went wrong,
and they shot the guard.
잠깐만요
Excuse me.
저 사람 대체 뭐 하는 거죠?
What the hell is he doing?
반장님
Captain...
이봐, 저 친구는 한 블록이나 떨어진
개 목에 걸린 등록증을 읽었어
Well, he did spot the dog's license
from a block away.
놈들은 검벌의 차로 달아났어요
Okay. They drove off in Gumbal's car.
남쪽으로 갔을 겁니다
They headed South.
가능한 한 서둘러서
사체를 버렸을 거고요
They're gonna dump it
as soon as they can.
- 이미 공항은 검문에 들어갔어요
- 그건 시간 낭비예요
- We're already checking the airport.
- No, that's a waste of time.
그쪽으로는 절대 안 갔을 겁니다
보안이 철저하잖아요
They would never go there.
There's too much security.
기차역 쪽을 알아보세요
Try the train station.
기차역이요?
Train station.
그러니까, 산 브루노나
밀브래 역 같은 데요
Yeah. Try, um, San Bruno...
or Millbrae.
경비원을 쏘고서
아마 상당히 당황했을 테니
They probably panicked
when they shot the guard.
이 근처 어딘가에 총이나
피 묻은 옷을 버렸을지도 몰라요
Maybe they dropped the gun or
some bloody clothes somewhere nearby.
뭡니까, 뭐 하는 거요? 세상에...
What, what are you
doing there? What...
이 개는 최근에 하수구 냄새를
맡으면서 돌아다녔나 봐요
this dog has been sniffing
around a sewer recently.
주변에 있는 하수구 뚜껑 보이시죠?
See these sewer grates around here?
범인들이 저기에 뭔가를 숨기는 걸
이 개가 봤을지도 모르죠
The perps might have stuffed
something down in there
and maybe this dog saw them do it.
농담이시겠죠
You gotta be kidding.
그냥 해보는 소리 맞죠?
말도 안 되는 소리예요
He's, he's kidding, right?
He's joking.
말도 안 되는 소릴 하고 있다고요
The man is joking.
확인해 보는 데는 2분이면 됩니다
It'll just take two minutes to check it.
경관!
Officer!
- 저 하수구 뚜껑을 열고 들여다보게
- 반장님!
- Take a look in that sewer grate.
- Captain.
개 냄새를 맡고 어찌 압니까?
From smelling a dog.
그런 추리는 불가능하다고요
That's impossible.
반장님!
Captain!
저분 말씀대로 이것들이
하수구에 감춰져 있었네요
They were stuffed down the drain
just like he said.
아뇨
No.
아뇨, 엄마
No, mom.
뉴스엔 안 나왔어요
I wasn't on the news.
기자들이 그때 현장에 없었거든요
Because there were no reporters
there yet.
실마리를 많이 찾았어요
I found a lot of clues.
3-4개의 대박 실마리를 찾았죠
I found three or four big clues.
반장님이 제 실력에 감동하시더라고요
Cap, captain was very impressed with me.
잠깐만요. 반장님이 들어오셨어요
직접 말해주실 테니 기다리세요
Wait. He just walked in.
He'll tell you. One second.
반장님, 저희 어머니신데요
Captain, it's my mother.
Tell her,
제가 현장에서 활약한 얘기
좀 해 주십시오
tell her how good
I was on the crime scene.
일즈 어머님
Uh, Mrs. Eels?
안녕하세요, 마티 실력이 좋더군요
정말 자랑스러우시겠습니다
Hi. Uh, yeah. Marty did great.
You'd be very proud of him.
일급 탐정이더군요
He's a first-rate detective.
저도 어머님을 한번 만나 뵙고 싶습니다
I look forward to meeting you too, ma'am.
예, 안녕히 계세요
Okay, bye-bye.
- 삑삑거리는 소리는 뭐였나?
- 아, 근무 중이시라 그래요
What were those beeps?
Oh, she was, she was at work.
퍼시픽 글로벌 항공에서 일하시거든요
She works for pacific global airlines.
품질관리 통화 감시원입니다
She's a, she's a quality
control operator.
이리 오세요
Come on. Come.
오셔서 앉으시죠, 앉으세요
Come on in. Sit down. Sit down.
여기요, 나탈리, 앉으세요
Here. Natalie, come sit down.
앉으시죠
Come sit down.
편하게 하세요
몽크 씨도 앉으시죠
Make yourself at home.
Monk, sit.
- 아무 데나 앉으세요
- 됐습니다, 별로 편치가 않네요
- Sit anywhere.
- Oh, that's okay. I'm not fine.
편치가 않다니 제가 제대로
들은 겁니까? / 그래요
- Did he just say he's not fine?
- Yeah.
그럼 반장님
제가 이 사건을 맡는 겁니까?
So, captain, am I on the case or what?
일단 몇 가지 질문부터 해야겠네
First, I have to
ask you a couple questions.
예, 그럽죠
Yeah, yeah.
어제 아침 8시에 어디 있었나?
Where were you yesterday morning
at 8:00?
강도가 일어난 시각 말입니까? / 응
You mean, when the robbery
was happening? / Yeah.
제가 강도랑 연관이 있다고
생각하시는 겁니까?
You guys think I had
something to do with that?
왜죠? 현장에서 했던 제 추리가
너무 뛰어나서요?
Why? Because you can't keep up
with me on a crime scene?
어디 있었나, 마티?
Where were you, Marty?
병원에 있었어요
I was at the hospital.
세인트 앤드류 병원이요
St. Andrew's.
뇌진탕이 생겼었다고 하더군요
They thought I had a concussion.
무슨 일이었는데요?
What happened?
그러니까...
Well...
좀 창피한 일이긴 합니다
제가...
That's kind of embarrassing.
I, um...
의뢰인에게 흠씬 얻어맞았죠
I got hit very hard by a client.
정말 아프게 맞았어요
Hit me very hard.
여기요, 그러니까...
Yeah. Um...
의뢰인의 부인을 미행해서
사진을 찍어다 주기로 했거든요
I was, um, supposed to follow
his wife and take pictures.
이런, 마누라가 바람을 피우고 있었구먼
Whoa. She was cheating on him.
아뇨, 아뇨, 남편입니다
No. No. That, that, that's him.
의뢰인이요
That's my client.
자기 아내랑 잠자리에 든 장면을
급습해서 사진까지 찍으신 거예요?
You burst in and took a picture
of a man in bed with his own wife?
예, 맞아요
실수를 했던 거죠
Yes, I did.
I made a mistake.
저도 인간이니까요
I'm human.
그러니 강도 사건이 일어났을 때
전 병원에 있었다는 게 결론입니다
So the bottom line is I was at the hospital
when the jewelry thing was happening.
- 병원에 확인해 보세요
- 그럴 거야
- You can call them.
- We will.
그냥 제가 추리를 잘했다고 믿기가
그렇게 어려우신가요?
Why is it so hard for you guys
to believe that I'm just this good?
왜냐면 마티, 이전엔 이렇게
잘한 적이 없었잖나
Because, Marty, you were
never this good before.
사실 형편없었지
In fact, you sort of sucked.
뭐, 독학 좀 했죠
집중하는 법도 익혔고요
Well, I, I've been teaching myself.
I've been, I've learned how to focus.
집중하는 게 진짜 비결이죠, 안 그래요?
- 평생교육원 이학 학사, 마티 일즈 -
And that's really the secret.
Focus, right?
제 말이 맞지 않나요?
Am I right about the focus thing?
베이 에어리어 평생교육원이면
Bay area center continuing education.
방송 통신 대학이 아닌가요?
Is that a correspondence school?
제대로 공인된 학교예요
It's fully accredited.
- 댁은 어느 학교를 나오셨는데요?
- 버클리요
- What school did you go to?
- Berkeley.
좋은 학교네요
That's a good school.
그쪽도 아마 제대로 공인된 학교겠죠
I believe they're fully accredited too.
예, 공인된 학교고 말고요
Yeah. Yeah, they're fully accredited.
그럼 제가 이 사건을 맡아도
되는 겁니까, 반장님?
So, captain, am I on the case or what?
저도 끼게 해 주세요
I mean, put me in, coach.
그 뭐냐, 스키 마스크도 찾아냈잖아요?
I found the, I found
the ski masks, didn't I?
이봐 마티, 내가 끼워주고 싶어도
Look, Marty, even if I wanted to,
자문 탐정을 둘이나 고용할
예산은 없다네
I just don't have the budget
to hire two consultants.
제, 제, 제 말, 제 말 들어 보세요
I, I, I tell you, I tell you what.
I tell you what.
성과를 내지 않는 한 전혀
보수를 주지 않으셔도 됩니다
You don't have to pay me dime one
unless I get some results.
그러니 손해 볼 거 없다고요
So this, this costs you nothing.
반장님, 잠깐만요
Captain, could I?
이 사람을 고용하시면 안 됩니다
You can't hire this guy.
- 범인들의 스키 마스크를 찾았잖아
- 개 냄새를 맡고 어떻게 알아요?
- He did find the ski masks.
- By smelling a dog.
말도 안 됩니다
It's not possible.
이봐, 몽크, 가끔은 자네가
실마리를 찾아내는 방식도
Look, Monk, sometimes
when you're picking up clues,
나한테는 마치 마술 같아 보이네
it seems like magic to me.
어떻게 그런 일을 하는지 모른다고
I don't know how you do it.
아마 저 친구도 자네가 이해하지
못하는 방식으로 일을 하는 거겠지
Maybe he's doing something
that you don't understand.
속임수를 쓰는 거라고요
I think he's cheating.
사기꾼입니다
He's a cheater.
디셔입니다
Disher.
초등학생처럼 굴지 마, 몽크
This isn't the fourth grade, Monk.
속임수를 쓰고 있어요
He's cheating.
- 어떤 속임수?
- 어떤 건지는...
How? / How.
저야 모르죠
I don't know.
지배인의 차를 찾아냈답니다
We just found the store manager's car.
어디 있었는지 맞혀 보세요
Guess where it was.
기차역 부근에?
Near a train station?
산 브루노 역이요
대단해요
In San Bruno.
Outstanding.
- 딱 맞히셨네요, 마티
- 가서 확인해 보자고
- You called it, Marty.
- Let's go check it out.
마티, 이리 오게
나랑 같이 타고 가지
Marty, come here.
You ride with me.
속임수라니까요
He's cheating.
실례합니다
Excuse me, excuse me, um,
- 계속하시죠
- 아니, 먼저 하세요
- go ahead.
- No, no. After you.
그럼 실례
Please.
참 괴상한 광경이죠?
Pretty weird, huh?
둘 중 하나를 집으로 보내야
될지도 모르겠군요
Maybe we should send one of them home.
그렇긴 한데 어느 쪽을?
Yeah, but which one?
마티 일즈예요
Marty Eels.
물고기랑 같은 철자의 E-e-l-s 죠
E, e, l, s like the fish.
우리 아들은 언제나
명탐정이 되고 싶어 했어요
He's always wanted to be a detective.
밤늦게까지 "용감한 형제" 얘기를
이불을 뒤집어쓰고 읽곤 했죠
He used to stay up late reading
hardy boys stories under the cover.
아드님께서 에이드리안 몽크를
돕고 계신 겁니까?
So your son is helping Adrian Monk?
누가 누구 도움을 받는 건지
그거야 모르죠
Who's helping who?
That's the question.
그게 아주 좋아요
I love that.
손을 움직이는 동작이
정말 좋아요
Love the, uh, the thing you do
with your hands.
- 옛날 탐정들 방식 같아서요
- 고마워요
- It's very old school.
- Thank you.
아니, 뭐 하는 겁니까?
What, what are you doing?
진흙을 보면
Mud.
차가 어디에 있었는지 알 수 있죠
You can tell where the car has been.
진흙 맛을 보고서?
From tasting it.
진흙 맛을 보고 있어요
He's tasting the mud.
- 그걸로 추리가 될까요?
- 안 되죠!
- Does that work?
- No!
돌아도 단단히 돌았어요
It's just nuts.
반장님, 지배인 키가 얼마나 됐죠?
Captain, how tall was the store manager?
면허증에는 177센티로 나와 있네요
Uh, 5'10" according
to his driver's license.
다른 사람이 이 차를
몰았나 보군요, 왜냐면
Somebody else was driving this car
because that,
이 의자는 179센티인 사람에게
맞도록 조절됐거든요
that chair has been adjusted
for somebody 5'11".
잠깐만, 잠깐만요
그런 걸 알아내진 못해요
Excuse me. Excuse me.
It's impossible to know that.
의자는 그렇게 정교하게
조절되지 않거든요
Seat adjustments are not that exact.
179센티라고 적어 둘까요?
Should I write down 5'11"?
모르겠네, 일단 적어 놔
Uh, I don't know. Yes.
연필로 적어
In pencil.
자, 봅시다
Well, here we go.
이 지도를 최근에 써먹었군요
This map was, uh, used recently.
그걸로 미루어...
That means that the, uh,
운전자가 이 지역은
익숙지가 않았나 봐요
the driver was not familiar
with this particular area.
- 나도 그건 알았어요
- 아무 말씀도 안 하셨잖아요
I, I, I had that one.
You didn't say anything.
제 차례가 오길 기다리고 있었죠
I was waiting my turn.
저도 알았어요, 반장님...
I had that one, captain...
속임수를 쓰고 있습니다
he's cheating.
사기꾼이에요
제가 쳐다보니까 확인한 거라고요
He's a cheater.
I, I, I, he saw me looking.
이 차는 47번 국도를 달렸군요
And this car was driven on Highway 47.
그걸 어찌 알게 되었나?
And how do you happen to know that?
자세히 보면 다 알아요, 반장님
차창에 붙은 죽은 벌레를 보세요
It's all in the details, captain.
See the dead bugs on the windshield.
회색 밴텀윙 모기입니다
This is a gray bantam wing mosquito.
어디에 가장 흔할까요?
Which are most common where?
아시는 분?
Anybody?
월터 크릭 저수지죠
Walter creek reservoir.
리빙스턴이죠! 47번 국도군요!
In Livingston. Highway 47.
정말 대단해요
That's fantastic.
밴텀윙 모기? 흥!
Bantam wing mosquitoes.
짐칸을 열어 보죠, 여러분
몽크 씨도 오세요
Gentlemen, let's pop the trunk.
Monk.
이 핏자국은 최근에 났군요
This blood is still fresh.
그렇군요
Yes, it is.
잘했어요
Good for you.
몽크 씨가 하나 찾았다고
적어 둬요
Write that down.
One for Monk.
좋아요, 검벌을 차에서
끌어낸 다음
All right, Gumbal was
dragged out of the car.
이 숲 속으로 옮겼을 거예요
And into these woods.
그렇군, 절 따라오세요
Okey-doke. Here we go.
이 이파리들을 최근에
누군가가 밟았군요
These leaves were recently crushed.
난 체로키 인디언의
116대 후손이거든요
I'm one-sixteenth cherokee.
멋진데요
그럴지도 모른다고 생각했는데
Cool. I thought he might be.
- 지금 뭐 하는 거죠?
- 눈뜨고 볼 수가 없군요
- Now what's he doing?
- I can't look.
수맥 찾는 막대기를 쓰고 있어
Oh, he's using a divining rod.
인디언들이 쓰던 방식이죠
The indians used to use them.
체로키 인디언의 116대 후손이래요
He's one-sixteenth cherokee.
오오, 제 아들이에요
Ooh, that's my boy.
다들 잘 보이시죠?
Can everybody see okay?
사진 많이 찍어 줘요
필름 값도 싸잖아요
Take lots of pictures.
Film is cheap.
지배인을 찾아냈습니다
I've got found the store manager.
물러서요, 물러서!
Stay back! Stay back!
여기서 다들 나가요
Get outta here!
다들 물러서요
이 사람들 여기서 내보내
Back off, back off.
Get these guys outta here.
가슴에 총상을 입었어
He was shot in the chest.
검시관 사무실에 연락해
감식반 부르고
Call the coroner's office.
Get the crime scene guys up here.
다들 당장 반경 6미터
이상 떨어지게 해!
And give me a 20-foot perimeter now!
좋아요, 모두 움직여요
반장님 말씀 들으셨죠!
All right, let's go.
You heard the man!
10걸음씩 뒤로 가세요!
움직여 주세요!
Take ten steps back!
Let's go, let's go!
이것들 여기서 치워 주고
물러서세요. 어서
Get these things outta here.
Baker, come on,
이 사람들 물러나게 해!
move these guys down!
- 흥미로운데요
- 뭐가요?
- That's interesting.
- What?
모르시겠어요?
You don't see that?
팔을 보세요
Look at his arms.
- 부자연스러운 위치잖아요
- 부자연스럽다니 뭐가요?
- That is an unnatural position.
- What? Unnatural?
우리한테 뭔가 알려주려 한 것 같아요
I think he was trying
to tell us something.
마지막 숨을 몰아쉬면서
메시지를 남기려 했던 거죠
With his dying breath,
he was trying to send us a message.
"마지막 숨을 몰아쉬었"대요
With his dying breath.
자기를 죽인 범인의 이름을
알려 주려 했던 거예요
He was trying to tell us
the name of the man who killed him.
보세요
Look.
자기 시계를 손가락으로
가리키고 있어요
He's pointing to his watch.
전혀 아닌데요
No, he's not.
반장님, 이런 짓을 할 만한 전과자
중에 카시오란 이름은 없습니까?
Captain, are there any perps who
do a job like this by the name of Casio?
카시오?
(시계 제조업체 이름)
Casio?
- 레프티는요?
- 반장님!
Lefty? / Captain.
다이얼은요?
Dial?
에디 다이얼이라고 있어요
Eddie Dial.
유괴 및 은행 강도 혐의로
폴섬 교도소에서 7년을 살았죠
He just did seven years in Folsom
for kidnapping and bank robbery.
막 가석방됐습니다
He just made parole.
- 좋아, 그자를 조사해보세
- 예, 반장님
- Well, let's check him out.
- Yes, sir.
베이커! 존슨!
Baker!
Johnson!
엄마, 제 카메라 못 보셨어요?
Mom, have you seen my camera?
웃옷은 살펴봤니?
Did you check your jacket?
- 주머니는 다 봤고?
- 찾아봐야 할 데는 찾아봤죠
- What about your pockets?
- Yes. I looked everywhere.
글쎄 난 못 봤는데
Well, I haven't seen it, honey.
몽크 아저씨에게 도와 달라고
부탁드려 보렴
Why don't you ask Mr. Monk to help you?
몽크 아저씨, 부탁드려요
견학 사진이 몽땅 들어있거든요
Please, Mr. Monk, it has all
my photos in it from my school trip.
공식 사진을 제가 찍었기 때문에
그걸 잃어버리면 낙제하게 될 거예요
I was the official photographer.
If I lose it, I'm going
to get an incomplete.
마지막으로 어디서 봤니?
When did you see it last?
어제 거실에서요
I saw it yesterday in the living room.
저 화분은 최근에 움직인 흔적이 있군요
That plant has been moved recently.
맞아요, 어떻게 아셨어요?
That's right.
How did you know?
식물은 보통 햇빛 쪽으로 굽어지죠
Normally they lean toward the sun.
이 녀석은 반대쪽으로 굽어 있네요
This one is leaning the other way.
여기 있구나
Hello.
몽크 아저씨, 정말 고맙습니다
Oh, Mr. Monk, thank you so much.
- 최고예요, 최고의 명탐정 아녜요?
- 최고다마다
You're the best.
Isn't he the best?
There's no one better.
You really are amazing. / Ha!
- 정말 대단하세요
- 하하!
잠깐만요
Wait.
여기에 언제 물을 주셨나요?
When did you water this?
아, 그게, 오늘 아침인데요
Oh, uh, this morning.
카메라가 오늘 아침 이전엔
여기 있지 않았던 것 같네요
The camera could not have been
back there this morning.
있었다면 물에 젖었겠죠
It would've gotten wet.
격려해주려고 한 거 고맙다, 줄리
Thanks for trying, Julie.
엄마가 시킨 거예요
My mom put me up to this.
몽크 씨는 정말 대단하다니까요
Mr. Monk, you really are amazing.
세계최고의 명탐정일 거예요
You're probably the best in the world.
마티란 사람도 제대로 보셨어요
사기꾼 맞아요
And you're right about
this Marty character. He's cheating.
- 글쎄요
- 맞다니까요
- I don't know.
- He is.
여보세요
Hello?
예, 반장님
Yes, sir.
정말이에요?
Really?
알았습니다
그리 곧 갈게요
Okay, okay. We're on our way.
살인범들 중의 하나를 잡았대요
지금 심문 중이라고 하네요
They just caught one of the killers.
They're questioning him now.
줄리, 금방 갔다 올게
Julie, we'll be back soon, honey.
나탈리, 잡힌 사람이
에디 다이얼은 아니었죠?
Natalie, it's not Eddie Dial, is it?
맞아요
Yeah.
네가 묵던 모텔 방에서
지배인의 지갑을 찾았어, 에디
We found the manager's wallet
in your motel room, Eddie.
다 끝났어
It's over.
넌 잡힌 몸이라고
We own you.
이봐요, 난 아무도 안 죽였다고요
Look, man, I didn't hurt anybody, okay?
총도 갖고 있지 않았는데요
I didn't even have a gun.
글쎄, 에드워드
두 사람이나 죽었잖아
Well, two people are dead, Edward.
누가 총을 쐈지?
Who did the shooting?
이놈이 죽였다는 데
돈 걸어도 좋아
I'm willing to bet you
it was that guy.
빅터 P 블랭챠드
Blanchard, Victor P.
너희 둘이 지난 주말에
함께 있는 게 목격됐어
The two of you were
seen together last weekend.
- 이놈 어디 있지, 에디?
- 몰라요
- Where is he, Eddie?
- I don't know.
반장님, 제가 해볼까요?
Captain, may I?
네 동업자 어디 있지, 에디?
Where's your, where's
your partner, Eddie?
모른다니까요
I don't know.
흠, 진실을 말하고 있어요
정말 모르는군요
Hmm, he's telling the truth.
He, he doesn't know.
지도 있습니까?
Do you have a map?
마치 인간 거짓말탐지기처럼 행동하네요
He's like a human lie detector.
믿기지가 않아요
I can't believe it.
나도 안 믿기네
I can't believe it either.
직접 보시고 계신 데도요?
He's doing it.
그래도 안 믿어져
I still don't believe it.
건넛방에서 벌어지고 있는 건
말도 안 되는 일이라고
What you see happening
in the next room, it's impossible.
정말...
It's just...
이게, 이게 뭐지?
What, what's this?
에디가 묵던 모텔 객실에서
발견한 물품입니다
Stuff we found in Eddie's motel room,
코스타리카 행 비행기 표 2장도 있어요
including a pair of tickets to Costa rica.
- 보석은 찾으셨나요?
- 아뇨, 아직
- Did you guys find the jewels?
- No, not yet.
- 마티가 찾아 줄 겁니다
- 좋아
Marty'll find them.
All right.
그러면 말인데, 에디
Now, then, Eddie,
보석을 어디다 숨겼지?
where did you hide the jewels?
Was it,
여긴가?
Was it here?
아니라 이거지, 그럼 여기?
No. Uh, was it here?
아니라고?
No.
그럼 여긴 어때?
Uh, how about here?
아하, 열이 좀 나네요
Ah, getting warmer.
여기다 보석을 숨겼나, 에디?
Did you hide them here, Eddie?
그래! 맞군
Ah! Yes.
주립공원에 있답니다
They're in the state park.
어디 보세
Get outta here.
이곳은 잘 알고 있어
바로 여기에 급수탑이 있지
I know this area.
There's a water tower right here.
그 급수탑 부근에 숨겼지, 에디?
Did you, uh, did you hide
them near the water tower, Eddie?
정답이랍니다!
Bingo!
찾았어요!
Yes!
공원관리 부서의 던롭에게 연락해서
거기서 기다리라고 전해
Call Dunlop in the parks department.
Tell him to meet us there.
- 삽도 좀 챙겨 오라고 하고
- 알겠습니다
- And tell him to bring some shovels.
- Yes, sir.
대체 뭐라고 보고서에 적어야
할지 도무지 모르겠군
I don't know how the hell
I'm gonna write this up.
마티
Marty.
아, 몽크 씨
Oh, Mr. Monk.
좋아, 먼저 가 봐
현장에서 보자고
All right, why don't you guys go ahead?
I'll meet you there.
디셔 경위다
주립공원 주변 2블록을 통제해 줘
This is Disher. Get me two block away
down the state park right now.
속임수를 쓰고 있다니까요
He's cheating!
그래, 몽크, 어떤 속임수를 쓰고 있는데?
What, Monk? How is he cheating?
용의자에게 막 자백도 받았고
We've got a suspect who just confessed.
없어진 차도 찾았고
시신까지 찾아냈어
He found the car.
He found the body.
거의 혼자 힘으로
이 사건을 해결하고 있다고
He is solving this case single-handedly.
속임수라니까요!
By cheating!
- 나탈리 생각은 어때요?
- 전 제 고용주 말을 믿어요
- Natalie, what do you think?
- I believe my boss.
어쨌든 그만 가봐야겠습니다
Anyway, we, we better go.
한 차에 탈까요
두 차로 나눠 갈까요?
Should we take one car or two cars?
몽크, 여기서 기다려 주겠나?
Monk, why don't you stay here?
이 사건은 마티가 해결하게 하겠네
We're gonna let Marty take this one.
잠깐, 잠깐만요
Whoa, whoa, wait, wait.
- 몽크를 해고하시게요?
- 아니요
- You're firing him?
- No. No.
마티가 진상에 접근해
있는 것 같으니까
Um, it's just that Marty
seems to be in a zone.
이 건은 전적으로 맡긴다는 뜻입니다
He's got a handle on this one.
다음 사건은 자네가 맡아, 알았지?
You get the next one, okay?
전화 드리죠
I'll call you.
가보겠습니다
I gotta go.
보석을 찾았나요?
So that found the jewels?
마티가 말한 딱 그 자리에 있었죠
They were right where Marty
said they'd be.
볼 것도 없이요
Of course.
그래서 경찰에서 손을 떼고
물러나 있으라고 요구했다고요?
And what, then they asked
you to step aside?
마티가 제 역할을 할 거랍니다
They said Marty was on a roll.
제가 그 양반 수사를 자꾸
방해할까 봐 그러는 것 같아요
I guess they didn't want
me to cramp his style.
에이드리안, 당연히 일시적으로
그러는 것일 겝니다
Well, Adrian, I'm sure
that this is all just temporary.
어쩌면 정말 저보다 나은지도 몰라요
Maybe he really is better than me.
뭐 그렇다고 그게 그렇게
받아들이기 힘든가요?
Yeah, well, would that be so terrible?
꼭 최고가 아니래도 뭐 어떻습니까?
I mean if you weren't number one?
풀톤 대학에서 형법을 가르치는
전직 경찰을 알고 있어요
An ex-cop I know teaches
criminal justice at Fulton college.
작년에 저한테 일자리를
제안했었죠
He offered me a job last year.
그 사람한테 전화해 볼까 싶네요
Maybe I'll give him a call.
- 그럼 그냥 포기하는 거군요
- 그래요
- All right, so you're just giving up.
- Okay.
안 돼요, 에이드리안
그냥 포기하라는 게 아니에요
No, no, Adrian, I'm not suggesting
that you just give up.
제 말의 요지는 언제나 당신보다
나은 사람이 있다는 거예요
I'm saying to you that there is
always someone ahead of you.
인간이니 그럴 수 있죠
This is the human condition.
이를테면
For instance, there,
로웬스턴이라고 시내에 새로
개업한 정신과 전문의가 있어요
there's a new psychiatrist here
in town, name of Lowenstern.
저로서는 결코 그 친구 실력을
쫓아갈 수가 없다는 걸 안답니다
Now, I know that there is no way that
I will ever be, well, as good as he is.
알고도 어쩔 수 없으니
현실을 받아들이는 거죠
I know this. I accept it.
선생님보다 낫다고요?
He's better than you?
정말 뛰어나답니다
노벨상 후보에 오른 적도 있고요
He's brilliant.
Nominated for a Nobel prize.
하지만, 중요한 건 몽크 씨가
가르치는 걸 좋아하느냐죠
But, the point is, you think
that you might enjoy teaching.
글쎄요
로웬스턴 얘기 좀 더 해 주세요
I don't know.
Tell me more about this Lowenstern.
로웬스턴을 소개해 드릴까요?
병원은 바로 길 건너에 있거든요
Lowenstern. I could introduce you.
Office is right across the street.
시간당 400달러를 청구하죠
He charges $400 an hour.
저기 어디까지 얘기했었죠?
So where, where were we?
어디까지 했더라...
Okay.
안녕하세요
Oh! Good morning, boss.
그것들은 둥근 스펀지에서 떨어진 거니까
They were out of the round sponges.
당황하지 마세요, 제가
귀가할 때 주워서 가져가죠
Don't panic, I'll pick some
up on the way home.
먹을 거는 염려하지 마시고요
Don't worry about the groceries.
풀턴 대학에 데려다 주세요
약속을 했거든요
You're driving me to Fulton college.
I have an appointment.
지금 당장이요?
You mean now?
- 11시요, 학과장을 만나거든요
- 그만두려고요?
11:00. I'm meeting the dean.
You're just gonna quit.
그냥 그렇게요?
Just like that.
강의도 잘할 수 있겠다 싶었어요
I think I would make a very good teacher.
설마요, 몽크 씨라면
형편없는 교육자가 될 걸요
Oh, Mr. Monk, you'd
make a terrible teacher.
숙제 하나 교정하는 데
4주는 걸릴 거잖아요
It would take you four weeks
to correct one paper.
탐정이 천직이에요
You're a detective.
명탐정이시라니까요
You're a great detective.
태워줄 거예요, 말 거예요?
Are you gonna drive me or not?
싫어요, 안 태워 줘요
No. No, I am not.
감정이 상해서 제대로 생각을
못 하는 것뿐이시잖아요
Your feelings are hurt
and you're just not thinking straight.
됐어요, 택시 잡을래요
Fine. Fine, I'll take a taxi.
택시를 타겠다고요?
You're gonna take a taxi?
택시에서 사람들이 무슨 짓을
하는 줄이나 알아요? / 그만!
- Do you know what people do in taxis?
- Fine!
됐어요, 직접 운전할래요
Fine, I will drive myself.
차를 빌리겠어요
I'll rent a car.
봤죠? 번호 누르고 있어요
See? I am dialing the number.
- 공갈 아니라고요
- 운전면허는 있어요?
- I'm not bluffing.
- Do you even have a driver's license?
그럼요, 면허 있어요
Yes, I have a license.
자, 다 됐어요
Okay, this is it.
이게 전화번호 마지막 숫자예요
번호 맞게 눌렀어요
This is the last digit.
I have dialed the number.
울리고 있다고요
It is ringing.
캐논 렌터카에 전화 주셔서 감사합니다
Thank you for calling Cannon rent-a-car.
이 전화는 서비스 품질관리
차원에서 모니터 됩니다
This call may be monitored
for quality purposes.
대기 상태예요
I am on hold.
몽크 씨, 풀턴 대학은
160킬로는 떨어져 있고
Mr. Monk, Fulton college is 100 miles away.
주간(州間) 고속도로를 타야해요
It is up the interstate.
- 다리도 건너야 하고요
- 알고 있어요
- It's over a bridge.
- I know.
다리를 건널 때는
눈가리개를 할 거예요
I have a blindfold for going over bridges.
- 직접 운전할 거라면서요?
- 좋은 지적이에요
But you'll be driving.
Good point.
그래도 할 수 있을 것 같아요
I think I can make it.
가리개 밑으로 살짝 보면 되죠
I'll just sort of peek underneath.
절대 운전하게 둘 수 없어요!
I'm not gonna let you drive!
평생 운전해서
다리를 건너본 적이 없잖아요
You've never driven
over a bridge in your life.
그럼 달리 무슨 수가 있어요?
What choice do I have?
잠깐만요, 선생님?
Excuse me. Excuse me, sir?
예?
Yes?
제 딸이 풀턴 대학에 다니는데
My daughter goes to Fulton college.
다리를 건너실 필요는 없어요
You don't have to take the bridge.
둑길을 따라가시면 된답니다
You can take the causeway
all the way up.
- 저희 대화를 들으셨어요?
- 예
You could hear us?
Yes, sir.
저는 품질관리 통화감시원인데
I'm a quality control operator.
통화 내용을 모니터 합니다
I'm monitoring the call.
전 대기상태였는데요
I, I was on hold.
저흰 통화가 연결되자마자
내용을 들을 수 있답니다
Yes, sir. We start listening
as soon as you're connected.
어떤 얘기를 듣게 되는지
못 믿으실 걸요
You wouldn't believe the things I hear.
사람들이 황당한 소리 하고
싸우고...
People fooling around, people arguing.
그 사연만 엮어서
책으로 써도 되겠더군요
I could write a book about it.
대기 상태에서도
제 얘길 들으실 수가 있군요
You could hear me
while I was on hold.
맞습니다
That's right.
이런, 몽크!
정말 놀랄 노자군요
Hey, Monk! What a nice surprise.
이 사람은 샌프란시스코
잡지사에서 왔는데
This guy's from San francisco magazine.
제가 이 도시에서 결혼하고픈
10대 총각 중 한 사람이래요
I'm one of the ten most eligible
bachelors in the city.
믿어지세요?
Can you believe it?
마티, 얘기 좀 합시다
Marty, we need to talk.
별로 좋은 시기는 아닌데요, 냇
Not a good time, Nat.
지금 저보고 냇이라고 불렀어요?
Did you just call me Nat?
이봐요, 저랑 몽크 좀 찍어 주세요
Hey, hey! Get one with me and Monk.
안 돼요 / 아니 아니, 여기요
정말 대박인데요
No. / Here. No, no, no.
This is good.
정상급 두뇌들의 만남 같죠
It's like a summit of great minds.
필립 말로우가 셜록 홈즈를 만나다!
Philip Marlowe meets Sherlock Holmes.
어머니에 대한 얘긴데요
It's about your mother.
일하시다가 뭔가를
엿들으신 것 같거든요
A little something she might
have overheard while at work.
안 들려요, 음악이 너무 커서
아무것도 안 들려요
Can't hear.
The music's too loud. I can't hear.
5분 만 쉽시다
쉬세요
Take, take a five.
Take a five.
어떻게 다 알았는지 알아요, 마티
We know how you did it, Marty.
드디어 알아냈어요
We figured it out.
제가 뭘 어쨌다고요?
How I did what?
Didn't your mother ever
tell you that cheaters never win?
어머니께서 사기를 쳐선 절대
이길 수 없다고 안 가르치셨어요?
사실은 어머니가 생각해 내신 거죠?
Actually, it was your mother's idea.
퍼시픽 글로벌 항공회사에서
일하시니까요, 안 그래요?
She works for pacific
global airlines, doesn't she?
품질관리 부서에서 일하시죠?
In the quality control department?
그런데요?
Yeah, so?
품질관리 차원에서
통화 내용이 모니터 됩니다
Your call may be monitored
for quality purposes.
진상은 이렇습니다
Here's what happened.
블랭챠드랑 다이얼 두 살인범은
After the murderers, Blanchard and Dial,
모텔 객실에 들어온 다음
보석을 세어 보고 있다가
went back to their motel room,
counted their jewels.
코스타리카 행 비행기 표를 사려고
항공사에 전화했습니다
And then they called the airlines
to buy plane tickets to Costa rica.
대기 상태가 됐겠죠
They were put on hold.
그 친구들은 전혀 몰랐습니다
What they didn't know was
어머니께서 통화 내용을
이미 듣고 있다는 사실을요
that your mother was already
on the line monitoring their call.
한참을 대기 상태로
기다리고 있었음이 틀림없어요
They must have been on hold
for quite a while,
범행 전체를 다 말할 때까지요
because they talked about everything.
누굴 죽였는지
Who they killed,
어디에 차를 버렸는지
where they dumped the car,
심지어 어디에 마스크를 숨겼는지도요
even where they hid the masks.
하지만, 어머니는 경찰에 알리지 않고
당신에게 전화를 했죠
But she didn't call the police.
She called you.
일스 씨가 사건을 해결하는 데
필요한 모든 사항을 알려줬어요
And told you everything you needed
to know to solve the case.
적어도 해결하는 척하는데
필요한 것들을 말이지요
Or at least pretend to solve it.
정말 머리 좋으신 분이군요
You're a very smart man.
- 예, 진짜 명탐정이거든요
- 그러네요
Yeah, he's the real thing.
Yeah.
당연히 이 모든 것을 증명할
증거가 없다는 것도 아시겠네요
Of course, you realize you
have no proof for any of this.
항공사에서 전화 내용을
녹음하지 않습니까?
Don't airlines record phone conversations?
그럴 것 같군요, 냇
Yes, Nat, I believe they do.
당연히 그러겠죠
Yes, they certainly do.
하지만, 그런 통화 내용은 어쩌다가
실수로 지워지기도 하지요
But those conversations have
a way of being accidentally erased.
그러니 남는 건 저를 문제 삼는
몽크 씨의 말 뿐입니다
So it's really your word against mine.
게다가 누구 얘기를 다들 믿겠어요?
And who do you think
everyone's gonna believe?
명탐정 마티 일스일까요
The amazing Marty Eels or...
옛날에 잘 나갔던 사람일까요?
yesterday's news?
전화가 아주 불이 나요
사건, 사건이 밀려들어서요
Phone's been ringing off the hook.
Case, cases, cases.
이만 가주실래요?
Would you mind?
일스 탐정 사무소입니다
Hey, Eels investigations.
이봐, 마티
하나 제의할 게 있다
Hey, Marty, I got a proposition for you.
- 누구시죠?
- 빅이지, 만난 적은 없지만
- Who's this?
- My name's Vic. We never met.
그래도 내 동업자인
에디 다이얼은 알겠지
I think you know my partner,
though, Eddie Dial.
네놈과 네 친구들이
어제 잡아 가둔 놈
In fact, you and your friends
arrested him yesterday.
이 번호를 어찌 알았지?
나만 쓸 수 있는 선인데
How did you get this number?
This is my private line.
네 어머니가 쓰는 단축번호의
1번이 이 번호더군
It's the first number
on your mother's speed dial.
어머니?
My mother?
날 이딴 식으로 엿 먹여 놓고
슬쩍 빠져나갈 수 있을 줄 알았나?
Did you really think you could
screw with me and get away with it?
- 어머니 어디 계셔?
- 지금 보고 왔는데 무사하시더군
Where is she?
I just left her. She's fine.
아직은
For now.
어머니를 다시 보고 싶으면
내 말 잘 들어
If you wannna see her again,
listen carefully.
그 보석은 내 거야
The jewels belong to me.
- 되찾고 싶어
- 보석을?
- I want them back.
- The jewels?
던 가(街)에 있는 버스 정류장에
8시까지 보석을 갖고 와
Bring them to the Dunn street
bus terminal by 8:00.
위층에 있는 240번 로커에 넣어 둬
Put them in locker 240 on the upper level.
- 여분 열쇠는 내게 있어
- 잠깐만, 잠깐만!
- I got a spare key.
- Wait a minute! Wait, wait, wait.
보석은 내가 손댈 수 없어
I, I can't get to the jewels.
증거품이라서 경찰이 보관 중이야
They're, they're locked up.
They're in evidence.
넌 할 수 있어, 마티
You can do it, Marty.
네 얘기 다 읽었거든
이번 달 최고의 유명인사라며
I've been reading all about you.
You're the flavor of the month.
증거품을 조사해 보고 싶다고 말해 봐
Just tell them you wanna
examine the evidence.
범인을 끌어낼 덫으로 쓰고 싶다고
Tell you wanna use it to set a trap.
놈들에게 네가 뭐라고
말할지는 관심없어
I don't care what you tell them, okay?
보석이나 돌려줘
Just, just get them back.
아, 그리고 마티
Oh, and Marty.
- 뭔데?
- 경찰은 안 돼
What? / No cops.
혼자서 와
Come alone.
나한테 무슨 일이 생기기라도 하면
Remember, if anything happens to me,
네 어머니는 8시 20분에 죽는다
your mother's dead by 8:20.
기다려!
Wait!
몽크 씨, 몽크 씨!
Mr. Monk! Mr. Monk!
잠깐만요!
Wait!
잠깐만요, 몽크 씨
Wait, Mr. Monk!
잠깐만 기다려 줘요!
Mr. Monk, wait, wait, wait!
빅 블랭챠드가 방금 전화했는데
우리 어머니를 잡고 있어요
It's Vic Blanchard.
He just called. He's got my mother.
세상에 / 이런, 반장님께 연락하죠
- Oh...
- My god. I'll call the captain.
안 돼요, 경찰은 안 돼요!
No, no! No, no cops.
경찰을 부르면 어머닐 죽인댔어요
He said no cops or he'd kill her.
몽크 씨, 제발 절 도와 주세요
Mr. Monk, please,
you gotta help me.
선생님 말씀이 옳아요!
제가 뭘 하는지도 모르겠다고요!
You were right!
I don't know what I'm doing!
정말 모르겠어요
I don't.
어디 봅시다
Let's go.
다시 한번 기억해 봐요
All right. Discover this one more time.
전화에 대고 뭐 다른 거 말한 건
전혀 생각나지 않나요?
Can you think of anything else
he might've said on the phone?
경찰은 안 된댔어요
No cops!
경찰 냄새만 맡아도
엄마는 죽는댔다니까요
He said if he even smells a cop,
she's dead!
이런 이런, 마티, 벌써 10번째인데
아무도 경찰은 부르지 않아요
Oh, my gosh, Marty, for the tenth time,
no one's calling the cops.
나탈리 말이 옳아요
마티, 보세요
She's right. Marty, look.
놈이 8시까지 시한을 줬으니까
We know where he's gonna beat 8:00.
그전에 어머니를 찾아내면
경찰들이 놈을 잡을 수 있다고요
If we can find your mother
before that time,
then the cops can pick him up then.
- 저도 알아요
- 윽! 나탈리...
- I know, I know.
- Ah! Natalie.
- 치울게요
- 사방에 다 튀어서...
All right. / It's all over...
제가 치워요!
I'm on it!
마티, 제발 소파에 앉아 주세요
Marty, can you just please
sit on the couch, all right?
몽크 씨를 불안하게 만들고 계신다고요
You're making Mr. Monk very nervous.
좋아요, 한번 더 물어보죠
All right, one more time.
납치범이 "방금 보고 왔다"고
말했죠, 맞습니까?
Okay, the kidnapper said
he just left her, right?
그럼 놈이 전화한 장소에서
그다지 멀리 있지 않다는 건데
So she can't be too far
from where he made that phone call.
통화 내용에서
뭔가 기억나는 거 없어요?
Do you remember anything else
about the phone call?
- 이를테면요?
- 이를테면?
Like what? / Like what?
뭐든지요, 배경에 잡소리 같은 거
Anything, noises in the background.
- 몰라요?
- 모른대요
- I don't know!
- He doesn't know.
이건 내 생각도 아니었는데
엄마가 모두 시킨 거죠
This wasn't even my idea.
My mother made me do this.
엄마가 이런 일에
말려들게 한 거예요
She forced me into it.
저 같은 실패자가
She said it was the only way
a loser like me
was ever gonna be able
to solve a real crime.
진짜 범죄를 풀 수 있는
유일한 방법이라고 말씀하셨죠
- 재밌는 어머니시네요
- 이봐요, 제 어머니라고요
- She sounds delightful.
- Hey, that's my mother.
남의 어머니를 두고 그런 식으로
말하는 게 어디 있습니까?
Where do you get off talking
about somebody else's mother?
- 무슨 버르장머리예요?
- 마티, 알았으니까요
- What's wrong with you?
- Okay, Marty, Marty,
마티, 집중해 보세요
Marty, Marty, concentrate.
생각을 하려고 애써 주세요
Can you please just try to think.
분명 뭔가 들었을 겁니다
You must have heard something.
예...
Yeah, uh...
바닷소리요
An ocean.
- 바닷가였나 봐요
- 계속하세요
- I think he was near an ocean.
- There you go.
그리고 뭔가 '뗑' 하는 소리가
울리고 있었는데...
And there was, um, a ringing
like, like a clang.
- '뗑'이라
- '뗑'이고요...
Clang. / Clang...
음...
With, with a sound before it.
Um...
쿵, 뗑
Thud. Clang.
쿵! 뗑!
Thud! Clang!
알았어요, 잠깐만요
Okay, give me a minute.
쿵! 뗑!
Thud! Clang!
알았어요, 마티, 알았다니까요
Yeah, Marty, I got it.
쿵, 뗑
Thud, clang.
생각 좀 합시다
Let me think.
- 쿵, 뗑!
- 맞아요
- Thud, clang!
- Okay.
- 세상에, 여기 계시군요
- 그래요
- Oh, my god, she's here, she's here.
- Okay.
엄마, 엄마!
Mom! Mom!
마티, 안 돼요
혼자 떨어지지 말아요
No, Marty, don't, don't get separated!
우리랑 같이 있어요
You stay with the group!
마티, 집중을 해 봐요
Marty, I want you to focus.
집중할 수 있겠어요?
Can you focus?
좋아요, 놈은 전화로 8시 20분에
어머니가 죽게 될 거랬죠?
All right, the caller said that she
would be dead by, by, by 8:20, was it?
왜 8시 20분일까요?
8시 정각이나 8시 30분이 아니고?
Why 8:20? Why not 8:00 or 8:30?
8시 20분이라
8:20.
생각해 봐요!
Think!
생각 중이잖아요
I'm thinking.
- 더 열심히 생각해 봐요
- 직접 해 보시죠
- Well, think harder.
- Why don't you think?
- 전 유명한 명탐정이 아니잖아요
- 2시간 전에는 그러셨잖아요
Hey, I'm not the great big
famous detective.
Well, you were two hours ago.
나탈리!
Natalie!
왜요?
What?
- 8시 20분이에요
- 뭐가 8시 20분이죠?
- 8:20.
- What's 8:20?
만조 시각
High tide.
만조 시각 : 오후 8시 20분
간조 시각 : 오후 2시 37분
HIGH TIDE : 8 :20 PM
LOW TIDE : 2:37 PM
엄마
Mom!
- 엄마!
- 저거예요
- Mom!
- That's gotta be it.
마티, 가요!
Go, Marty, go!
엄마! 엄마!
Mom! Mom! Mom!
난 여기서 기다릴게요!
I'll wait out here!
뒤를 지켜줄게요!
I got your back!
엄마!
Mom!
엄마, 엄마!
Mom! Mom!
구해 드릴게요, 일스 부인!
We're trying, Mrs. Eels!
밀어요
Push!
얼른
Hurry!
세상에, 서둘러요
Oh, my god! Hurry!
서둘러요!
Hurry! Hurry!
마티, 얼른 서둘러요
Okay, Marty, you gotta hurry!
서둘러요!
Hurry! Hurry!
블랭챠드! 손 올려!
Blanchard! Hands up!
경찰입니다!
Police officers!
블랭챠드, 해럴드 검벌을
살해한 혐의로 체포한다
Blanchard, you're under arrest
for the murder of Harold Gumbal.
이리 와!
Come on, come on.
가자
Go.
좋아요, 고맙습니다
Great, thank you.
놈을 잡았대요, 다 끝났어요
They got him. It's over.
다행이군요
That's good.
일스 부인, 엿들으신 통화 내용에
대해서 진술을 하셔야 할 겁니다
Mrs. Eels, you're probably going
to have to testify
about that phone call you overheard.
이 사람에게 얘기했구나
You told him.
입도 뻥긋 안 했어요
I didn't tell him.
혼자서 다 알아냈죠
He figured it out.
진짜 명탐정이세요
He's a real detective.
사실 아드님이 어머님을 찾으셨어요
Actually, he found you.
저희는 전혀 파악 못 했죠
We had no idea where you were.
모든 실마리를 잘 조합했어요
He put all the clues together.
마티는...
He, um...
정말이지 제가 본 최고의
독특한 추리 기법을 쓰더군요
it really was some of the most
unique detective work I've ever seen.
너무 대단해서 거짓말 같았죠
Just an incredible detective.
- 추리하는 방식이 마치...
- 어떤데요?
I mean, his detecting is like...
What?
다른 사람의 도움은 필요 없겠더라고요
He doesn't need anyone's help, Mrs. Eels.
예, 도움은 필요 없겠어요
No. No one's help.
정말이에요?
Really?
납치범에게 전화가 걸려오니까
두 분은 완전히 공황에 빠지시데요
When the kidnapper called,
they both panicked.
저, 전 자주 당황하곤 하거든요
I, I, I'm prone to panicking.
제가 "집중하자!"라고 그랬죠
And I had to say, "let's get focused!"
우리 어머니가 곤경에 빠지셨으니까요
Because my mother's in trouble.
그래서 모두들 집중하기 시작했죠
And, and that got everybody focused.
하지만 그 다음엔...
But, but then I had to,
통화 배경에서 들렸던 소리를
기억하려고 집중했고
I had to concentrate
on sounds from the background.
파도 소리를 기억해냈죠
I could hear the ocean.
그 다음에 '뗑' '쿵' 소리를 기억했고
And, and I heard a clang and a thud.
'쿵' 다음에 '뗑'이에요
A thud and a clang.
'쿵' 다음에 '뗑'
And a thud and a clang.
그 다음에 8시 20분이래서
And, and 8:20,
왜 8시나 8시 반이 아닐까 하다가
why not 8:00? Why not 8:30?
8시 20분이 만조 시각이라는 걸
기억해 냈죠
And then I remembered
high tide is at 8:20.
실마리 조각들이 있으니까
모두 짜 맞춰지더라고요
Once I, once I had that piece,
then it all fell together.
마티, 정말 대단하구나
Oh, Marty. Marty, you're wonderful.
경찰 관계자 여러분
I'd like to thank
the police department,
특히 스토틀마이어 반장님과
에이드리안 몽크에게 감사드립니다
particularly captain Stottlemeyer
and, uh, Adrian Monk.
저에게는 아주 어려운 사건이었습니다
This was a very difficult case for me.
그래서 지난밤 결정을 내렸는데요
Uh, last night I, I made a decision.
제 경력에 있어 가장
어려운 결정이었습니다만
It's, it's the toughest
decision of my career,
탐정업을 그만두기로 했습니다
but I am going to, um, resign my practice,
이후 풀턴 지방대학에
강의직을 받아들여
and, uh, take a teaching position
at Fulton community college,
현대 범죄수사 기법을 가르칠 예정입니다
uh, where I'll be teaching
modern criminal investigative techniques.
자네가 저 사람을
바로 봤군, 안 그런가?
You were right about him, weren't you?
속임수를 쓰고 있었어
He was cheating.
미안합니다, 열쇠를 떨어뜨렸네요
Sorry, dropped the key.
사기꾼이 맞군
He was cheating.
번역수정
김철균(kim1047@nate.com)
한글교정
이미란(lmr0412@nate.com)
자막제작 - NSC 자막팀
(http://club.nate.com/tsm)